<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<TEI xml:space="preserve" xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0" 
xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" 
xsi:schemaLocation="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0 https://raw.githubusercontent.com/kermitt2/grobid/master/grobid-home/schemas/xsd/Grobid.xsd"
 xmlns:xlink="http://www.w3.org/1999/xlink">
	<teiHeader xml:lang="en">
		<fileDesc>
			<titleStmt>
				<title level="a" type="main"></title>
			</titleStmt>
			<publicationStmt>
				<publisher/>
				<availability status="unknown"><licence/></availability>
			</publicationStmt>
			<sourceDesc>
				<biblStruct>
					<analytic>
					</analytic>
					<monogr>
						<imprint>
							<date/>
						</imprint>
					</monogr>
					<idno type="MD5">4D130C9AEC615F6C8FDB215B508346E6</idno>
					<idno type="DOI">10.1177/09567976211042300</idno>
				</biblStruct>
			</sourceDesc>
		</fileDesc>
		<encodingDesc>
			<appInfo>
				<application version="0.8.0" ident="GROBID" when="2024-05-06T13:32+0000">
					<desc>GROBID - A machine learning software for extracting information from scholarly documents</desc>
					<ref target="https://github.com/kermitt2/grobid"/>
				</application>
			</appInfo>
		</encodingDesc>
		<profileDesc>
			<abstract>
<div xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><p><s>The primary goal of Psychological Science is to publish articles that make significant theoretical and empirical contributions to the psychological literature and that are methodologically and statistically rigorous.</s><s>Most of the pages of the journal further this goal through publication of Research Articles and, since 2017, Preregistered Direct Replication reports.</s><s>Another important function of the journal is to further scientific discourse around the topics covered in these empirical articles.</s><s>The main vehicle for these exchanges has been the Commentary and Reply to Commentary.</s><s>In this editorial, I announce some important changes to the Commentary/ Reply to Commentary format and introduce a new vehicle (new to Psychological Science, that is) that will make scientific exchanges more timely, dynamic, and accessible: Letters to the Editors.</s></p></div>
			</abstract>
		</profileDesc>
	</teiHeader>
	<text xml:lang="en">
		<body>
<div xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><head>Current State of Commentaries and Replies</head><p><s>Throughout its history, Psychological Science has featured Commentaries on articles published in the journal and given authors of the target articles the opportunity to reply to them.</s><s>As with all articles published in the journal, submissions to these formats are peer reviewed, and they are held to the same high standards as other articles in terms of empirical and theoretical significance.</s><s>These Commentaries/Replies to Commentary are popular.</s><s>On publication of virtually every issue, the editorial office receives inquiries about the possible publication of a Commentary on one or more of the featured articles, sometimes before the articles even make it into print.</s><s>This is good news: It is a sign of a healthy and vibrant scientific community.</s></p><p><s>The bad news about the Commentary/Reply to Commentary vehicle is that it can be very slow.</s><s>By the time a Commentary is accepted, months may have passed since publication of the target article.</s><s>Further slowing the process, editorial policy at Psychological Science is that authors of target articles are given the opportunity to submit a Reply to Commentary.</s><s>The invitation of a Reply is extended only once the Commentary is accepted.</s><s>Typically, the Commentary is held until the Reply is accepted, so that the Commentary and Reply can be published simultaneously.</s><s>The sometimes snail's pace of this process makes it less than ideal as a means of fostering scientific exchange over ideas generated by and discussed in articles published in the journal.</s></p></div>
<div xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><head>Bringing Letters to the Editors to Psychological Science</head><p><s>To address the need for a more timely and flexible means for scientific exchange over articles published in Psychological Science and to further open psychological science, we are bringing Letters to the Editors to the journal.</s><s>The Letters to the Editors manuscript type will not replace the Commentary/Reply to Commentary format, though it will usher in some changes to it (discussed below).</s></p><p><s>The Letters to the Editors manuscript type will permit authors 500 words to make a comment, express a concern, develop an alternative interpretation, report the outcome of a test for replication, or make some other contribution to scientific exchange over an article published in the journal.</s><s>The 500 words may be supported by up to 10 references (strictly enforced!),</s><s>though references are not required.</s><s>Letters to the Editors will not have an Abstract, Statement of Relevance, headings, or subheadings; tables and figures are not permitted.</s><s>Letters to the Editors will be reviewed by two members of the editorial team (Editor in Chief, Senior Editors, Associate Editors), who will decide whether the submission serves to further scientific exchange (though in some cases, the editors may seek an external review).</s><s>If "yes," authors of a letter will be permitted one round of revision.</s><s>Authors of articles that are the subject of a Letter to the Editors may reply with a letter of their own, which will undergo the same editorial process.</s><s>Generally, a given author (or authoring team) will be permitted only one letter on a target article.</s><s>A second letter by the same author (or authors) must be approved by the editorial team.</s></p><p><s>Letters to the Editors will be disseminated online only to permit more rapid publication and to keep the discussion timely and responsive.</s><s>They will be hosted on Figshare, which is an online open-access repository and the site that hosts all of the journal's Supplemental Material.</s><s>To further speed dissemination, accepted Letters to the Editors will not be copyedited or held for replies but instead will be disseminated as quickly as possible on acceptance.</s><s>Letters to the Editors will have DOIs but, fitting their existence in the liminal space between a formal publication and an unmediated social media conversation, they will not be indexed (i.e., discoverable through PubMed, PsycInfo, etc.).</s><s>To facilitate connections between the target article and Letters to the Editors, they will be linked to each other.</s><s>As well, the title of each publication in this format will begin "Letter to the Editors of Psychological Science," followed by a brief original title, followed by "Regarding [insert citation of the target article]" (the title will not count against the 500-word limit).</s><s>There also will be a landing page on the SAGE site for Letters to the Editors, which will be accessible from the main journal page.</s><s>This will permit readers to find Letters to the Editors even if they cannot remember the title or author of the target article.</s></p><p><s>Letters to the Editors are intended to be less formal than Research Articles or Commentaries yet still be governed by rules and guidelines.</s><s>The editors reserve the right to add further rules and guidelines as the format develops.</s><s>One absolutely inviolable rule now and forever is that Letters to the Editors must be civil.</s><s>Their purpose is to foster scientific exchange.</s><s>That purpose is served only when all parties to the conversation are respectful of one another.</s><s>Another rule is that there shall be no piling on.</s><s>Letters that make essentially the same point as another that has been published, accepted, or is under revision will not be considered, and the editors may limit the total number of Letters to the Editors on a given target article.</s><s>Letters to the Editors must be in response to-and make specific reference to-an article published in Psychologi cal Science.</s><s>Except under circumstances we expect will be rare, Letters to the Editors must be submitted within 1 year of print publication of the target article, thus helping to ensure that the conversation remains fresh.</s><s>(An exception to the 1-year time frame is the case of a report of a test for replication, which is likely to require more than 1 year to accomplish.)</s><s>Letters to the Editors will be submitted through the SAGE Track site (https://journals.sagepub.com/author-instructions/</s><s>PSS).</s><s>On submission, indicate that the manuscript type is "Letter."</s></p><p><s>To introduce the Letters to the Editors format to Psychological Science, I have invited three author groups to contribute letters.</s><s>Two of the letters form a pair regarding the study by <ref type="bibr">Nichols and colleagues (2020)</ref>.</s><s>I thank Gigi Luk, John A. E. Anderson, John G. Grundy, Christos Pliatsikas, and Jason Rothman for their Letter to the Editors about this article and Emily Nichols and Adrian Owen for their reply to the letter.</s><s>This exchange among scholars illustrates the type of scientific communication that stands to move the field forward and that I hope will be well represented in Letters to the Editors contributions.</s><s>The third letter is from Ilka Helene Gleibs and Nihan Albayrak-Aydemir, who report the outcome of a test for replication of the study by <ref type="bibr">Alves and colleagues (2018)</ref>.</s><s>They report a direct and independent replication of the major findings of the earlier article and discuss the implications of the outcome for future research and policy interventions.</s><s>I appreciate that these authors took me up on my invitation to disseminate their findings through this new format.</s><s>Thank you Luk and colleagues, Nichols and Owen, and Gleibs and Albayrak-Aydemir for getting us off to a strong start.</s></p></div>
<div xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><head>Changes to the Commentary Format</head><p><s>Whereas Letters to the Editors will provide the best mechanism for timely exchange, Commentaries remain the best vehicle for responses that feature new empirical data or analyses that, for example, elaborate, extend, or paint a different picture of the data reported in a target article.</s><s>Accordingly, hereafter, in light of the introduction of the Letters to the Editors format to Psy chological Science, Commentaries will be reserved for manuscripts that feature an empirical response (i.e., new data or new statistical analysis of existing data).</s></p><p><s>The format and editorial handling of Commentary submissions will remain the same.</s><s>The Reply to Commentary option will remain (though some authors of target articles may elect to make their reply through the Letters to the Editors manuscript type).</s><s>Except under extraordinary circumstances, we will publish only one Commentary/Reply per target article.</s><s>In the rare event of more than one Commentary, any given individual is permitted to be an author on one and only one Commentary.</s><s>Authors are not permitted to write a Commentary on their own work.</s></p></div>
<div xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><head>Conclusion</head><p><s>As is the case with most changes, I expect that introduction of Letters to the Editors and reservation of the Commentary category for empirical responses will be met with some cheers and some boos.</s><s>This introduction and change likely will disequilibrate the system, at least temporarily.</s><s>As a developmental scientist, I embrace that likely outcome because change brings not only vulnerability but also opportunity.</s><s>I look forward to the new opportunities for scientific exchange that will come with Letters to the Editors and the deepening of empirical insight that will come with the newly dedicated Commentary format.</s></p></div>
<div xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0"><head>Patricia J. Bauer</head><p><s>Editor in Chief</s></p></div><figure xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0" xml:id="fig_0"><head>1042300P</head><label></label><figDesc><div><p><s>SSXXX10.1177/09567976211042300BauerLetters Editorial editorial2021 A New Option for Scientific Exchange and an Alternative to the Commentary Format</s></p></div></figDesc></figure>
		</body>
		<back>
			<div type="references">

				<listBibl>

<biblStruct xml:id="b0">
	<analytic>
		<title level="a" type="main">A cognitiveecological explanation of intergroup biases</title>
		<author>
			<persName><forename type="first">H</forename><surname>Alves</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName><forename type="first">A</forename><surname>Koch</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName><forename type="first">C</forename><surname>Unkelbach</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<idno type="DOI">10.1177/0956797618756862</idno>
		<ptr target="https://doi.org/10.1177/0956797618756862" />
	</analytic>
	<monogr>
		<title level="j">Psychologi cal Science</title>
		<imprint>
			<biblScope unit="volume">29</biblScope>
			<biblScope unit="issue">7</biblScope>
			<biblScope unit="page" from="1126" to="1133" />
			<date type="published" when="2018">2018</date>
		</imprint>
	</monogr>
</biblStruct>

<biblStruct xml:id="b1">
	<analytic>
		<title level="a" type="main">Bilingualism affords no general cognitive advantages: A population study of executive function in 11,000 people</title>
		<author>
			<persName><forename type="first">E</forename><forename type="middle">S</forename><surname>Nichols</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName><forename type="first">C</forename><forename type="middle">J</forename><surname>Wild</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName><forename type="first">B</forename><surname>Stojanoski</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName><forename type="first">M</forename><forename type="middle">E</forename><surname>Battista</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<author>
			<persName><forename type="first">A</forename><forename type="middle">M</forename><surname>Owen</surname></persName>
		</author>
		<idno type="DOI">10.1177/0956797620903113</idno>
		<ptr target="https://doi.org/10.1177/0956797620903113" />
	</analytic>
	<monogr>
		<title level="j">Psychological Science</title>
		<imprint>
			<biblScope unit="volume">31</biblScope>
			<biblScope unit="issue">5</biblScope>
			<biblScope unit="page" from="548" to="567" />
			<date type="published" when="2020">2020</date>
		</imprint>
	</monogr>
</biblStruct>

				</listBibl>
			</div>
		</back>
	</text>
</TEI>
